I've been in those conversations where
I'm like we can't use that we can't use
the cool new thing how do we make this
old thing work for us so I get it the
other piece of course is the agent could
respond I don't know this was really
important for me when we were evaluating
different tools to put on the
documentation because the documentation
at the end of the day is the source of
Truth for how you work with the product
so I'm sure we've all been in a
situation where we're looking at this
thing going is this AI agent going to
like work with me to give me what I
need you're listening to the AI native
Dev brought to you to fight
[Music]
Tesla and on today's episode we have
Amara Graham from kunda head of
developer experience and we're going to
be talking about documentation and how
AI can help us with documentation both
looking at writing documentation reading
documentation whether documentation is
useful or not useful how we can test
whether the documentation is accurate
for our users and so for Mara welcome to
the session how are you I'm great thanks
for having me absolutely no problem and
tell us a little bit about yourself
Amara and a little bit about kunder as
well so maybe your background what you
do what head of developer experience
means and so forth at kunda we run our
documentation which is part of the
reason why I'm here today as well as
some of the more like Hands-On technical
components so we are responsible for
what I like to say is everything after
the product or product adjacent tooling
so that could include API reference how
to work with the API including things as
technical as SDK so a lot of things that
developers are are touching and Interac
AC in with but taking a little bit of a
step back I've been in Devil I feel like
I looked this up yesterday for a number
of years I started as a developer
Advocate after I decided that heads down
development really wasn't for me I was
in an Enterprise context I'm following
the path of this three pillar program
devil approach Community advocacy
developer experience but in the here and
now I'm deep in the developer experience
space yeah tell us a little bit about
what you do there as about what comma
does yes so I don't have the the
polished marketing pitch so if Anya is
listening I'm so sorry as I butcher this
it just say it's another commment fine
it's a different commment we do process
Automation and orchestration which again
is is very Central to my background in
development where I started doing
process orchestration before we were
calling it orchestration but at kunda
it's all about bringing together the
process that you want to automate and
then all of the pieces that do that
automation
that's super vague it could be something
like you have a task list that people
need to go through to say okay how do I
do approvals how do I do those two-step
processes where someone creates a thing
you approve it boom it goes through you
need a portal experience all the way
through to things that are completely
automated touchless so you want to
integrate with a number of different
systems Enterprise or not we tile those
things together for you we have a a
combination of the what I would describe
as like a traditional workflow tool so
you can visually see how something goes
through the process whether it's a set
of uis or some of more of those like
backend truly automated things and then
of course all of the kind of wiring to
make that actually happen yeah and and
in terms of the Persona then that would
be the main user for command are you
looking at more of a platform role a
devops role a bit of development or a
bit of a mix that's a great question it
includes some of the people who are
doing that traditional software
engineering but the real answer is it
includes everyone so that could be the
devops folks supporting the actual like
platform infrastructure but it's also
going to include people who are building
those
applications directly that interact with
the the engine so from the documentation
users point of view when you're thinking
about creating documentation which leads
us nicely into this topic you're
essentially I guess the person you're
writing for is an engineer of some kind
whether they're leaning more onto the
platform side or onto the software
engineer inside talk us through a little
bit about the tools that you use or
maybe even the thought process that you
went through when you're thinking about
needing to offer the highest level of
documentation that you could what went
through your mind in terms of did we
choose an AI style solution that can
assist us with that or do we do the more
traditional let's have humans write
everything let's have humans provide
that based on the question and requests
that come in provide that back to the
user that's a very big question that you
just asked or set of questions that you
asked because we have so many different
kinds of users there's a a line that we
kind of have to walk between how do we
enable all of our users to be able to
interact and understand our product and
then how do we deeply enable our most
technical users in our documentation it
starts with structure and we're going to
have some people who come in and say I
need a really superficial understanding
of how the product works and how I could
apply it to my use cases to my
organization and then you're also going
to have the people who are coming in and
say not only do I need to understand
deep use cases but I need to understand
how do I apply them immediately so the
very very technical side of the the
documentation because we have this
disparity in users we have to have a
spectrum of content and with that we
have to have a way to enable those
people that are at any point in the
journey whether they're beginners to
kunda they deeply understand process
orchestration or this is like something
totally foreign to them in all manners
of the term so when we're looking at
ways to enable this very broad set of
users we can't just say Okay developers
are super comfortable with things like
Early Access tooling the late greatest
bleeding edge thing they'll totally
understand interacting with an AI agent
we need to be a little bit more gentle
with that because we don't always know
who's coming to the the docs and what
they're coming for when we're looking at
the doc structure we're trying to make
sure that we can introduce all of these
different personas but we also want to
get on that AI hype train if you will so
we know that people are changing some of
their behaviors one of the biggest
changes that we've seen is around
searching and how they find different
pages how they find the content that
they're looking for that very naturally
led us to looking at how do we go from
just doing the like text based searching
of like keywords and things like that to
how do we introduce something that is
going to offer our users a dialogue so
introducing an AI agent and introducing
it in a way that feels safe that allows
some folks in like our Enterprise
context to maybe interact with something
like that for the first time in a
business context and how do we do it in
a way that people are truly comfortable
with it and trust it and don't run to
our support agents to say can you help
me find this in the docs when they're
like I'm just going to search and yeah
couldn't you just do that it's been
really interesting to see how we need to
evolve our tooling to meet the needs of
our users not just our developers but
one of those things that we're doing is
trying to do it in a a gentle way that
gives them that encouragement to say
interacting with something like an AI
agent on our docs is something that you
should do is that first round of
knowledge Gathering or
troubleshooting and again I just can't
emphasize enough like being very gentle
about it because there's some people who
are going to say no give me the the
human I want to talk to a human and
interact with a a person to guide me
through this experience so that agent
then it's essentially a chat UI right
it's it's directly through the commer
site what kind of input does that take
in terms of providing an answer back to
the user will it differ based on things
like the experience of the user or will
it pivot based on the how the questions
asked or the style of the questions
asked or does it not necessarily care
too much about who the user is it's just
trying to find that best match on the
actual answers that exist in the
documentation and provide that back yeah
I'm not going to say it's that smart yet
and it's not doing a lot of like
additional analytic sourcing I'm going
to call it it's maybe not the best term
to use yeah but it's really taking
things at face value and it maybe is
lessening the value if I say it's like
superpowered search but that's really
the way that I want to describe it
because it's that next evolution in
you've gone from keyword-based search to
something a little bit more powerful
again I say I'm coming with my
Enterprise background I know many of our
customers are in an Enterprise context
where safety is really important so this
idea that it's not going to pull like
their browser history or something very
invasive like that but as you're having
these conversations with an AI agent it
should pick up some context right it
should have some concept of history as
it goes through so with our users I want
to make sure that they understand that
the the context that we're getting
within that conversation is going to
help them find the the resources that
they're looking for within the
documentation a way to introduce the
agent concept but it's also a gentle way
to introduce them to something that is
beyond just a a keyword search yeah
absolutely and and in terms of
interestingly we had Tamar from glean on
she was talking about how users have a
better response or better answers when
they realize they're talking to a chat
UI so if they pass in just search terms
they won't get as good an answer as if
they were to actually have that chat
style conversation have you done any
research on on how users get results
based on whether they're looking at more
search style input or whether it's chat
input or have you seen any differences
that I've seen differences but only
because a tool that is Kappa they have a
a great set of kind of backend analytics
and dashboards that I can look at and
it's interesting to see we don't get a
lot of engagement on did people
ultimately end the
conversation with what they felt like
they were looking for so we have the
ability to get like a thumbs up thumbs
down from them but what's interesting is
I can infer if the person felt like the
the conversation was successful or not
and many times it has to do with the
fact that we have some users who are
coming into it with that chat GPT style
of I'm gonna have a dialogue with this
agent this is great I'm going to talk to
it exactly like I would a human full
sentences and everything and then we
have other users who are still using it
as more of a search function which
almost tickled by because we also have a
search box like it's two separate things
two separate very clear experiences and
we did that intentionally but that's
some of the things that I'm trying to
dig into is how do we validate that the
docs are good through tooling like this
are people able to find what they need
and can they use the tooling that we
offer successfully so if they're just
using the AI agent like a search box
that doesn't really unlock the value
that we're looking for but it does give
us an idea of how our users will
interact with this Tooling in the future
so maybe we change how we position that
or maybe we even offer some sort of
instruction to say this is how you use
this and this is how you'll be able to
find that information faster quicker
better yeah and in terms of success I
guess there's two levels of success here
one is was the agent able to provide the
documentation that was requested and I
guess the second one is maybe it's the
right documentation but was the
documentation good or bad how do you uh
ascertain that level of success from the
request yeah so there's a a couple of
different things going on from the the
tooling itself within Kappa we have the
ability to see does the agent respond in
a way that it feels is uncertain so on
the dashboard itself we get an uncertain
tag at least once a month um my team and
I are going in and evaluating what are
the topics or what are the conversations
that are coming up as uncertain and
that's a great way for us to dig in and
see is it the agent that's getting
confused is it the user that was
initially confused and if you ever been
so lost you're like I don't know how to
find myself I don't know how to unstick
myself from where I'm at we go through
and evaluate like what's happening in
that context or in that conversation the
other piece of course is the agent could
respond I don't don't know this was
really important for me when we were
evaluating different tools to put on the
documentation because the documentation
at the end of the day is the source of
Truth for how you work with the product
there are contractual agreements aligned
to that terms and conditions like it has
to be very clear and very accurate so if
the agent responds I don't know that's
good in the sense that like we want to
make sure it's not hallucinating it's
not going in the direction of making
something up and potentially misleading
users but it also Flags to us are there
gaps in our documentation did somebody
ask a question that we should be able to
answer and then we launch a little bit
of an investigation to understand how we
want to address that is it a docs Gap is
it a product Gap is it something that we
know we'll never work on and then in the
AI back end itself we can go and add
like a specific answer if we need to so
that's maybe a short-term solution or
even a long-term solution if we say ooh
this is not something that we're ever
going to do it's interesting that we
have somebody asking this and then maybe
that's something again that we flag to
product management or product marketing
to say maybe people are misunderstanding
how we are marketing our product and how
do we want to address this it's not
necessarily A documentation issue as
much as it's a positioning of the the
product issue yeah interesting so
there's a few things that we can
definitely unpack so I think the I don't
new no case is is a really tough one is
that solved by Kappa or is that a layer
that you add on top of Kappa it is
solved by kappo which I'm very thankful
for yeah absolutely and the workflow
there then if you user gets an I don't
know back from Kappa does that then
encourage them to or does it
automatically reach out to someone on
the services team or someone on your
team or does that just get fed back to
the team as data how does that resolve
we've done a couple of different things
it does not reach out or I know some
flows will say okay let me route you to
like a human agent we don't do anything
quite like that today but it does try to
to Route people to things to further
help themselves in our documentation we
do reference like our community Forum we
do link to our traditional support
tooling so it can prompt for if you want
additional help or you want to continue
this conversation in a different space
or with involved it does route people to
those places and spaces but it is not
one of those traditional support tools
where it says okay let me get a live
agent for you to to discuss not
something that we're looking for and I
think it's not something that our our
users are interested in I think many
times they're quite happy to get that
response and go ah okay I'll do my own
digging do a little research is this
maybe just not on the road map yet and
then it takes a little bit more
investigative journalism if you will on
my part to go through but every once in
a while I see something pop up on like
internal slack channels where I'm like
that's very interesting that this
question is coming up because it looks
very similar to something that I saw
recently and it's customer a is
requesting this and was curious about
the road map I think customer a is this
person on the dots but it's all
Anonymous so I can't quite relate it
back just that investigative journalism
side of things where I'm like I
connected enough dots and I think this
is the same thing yeah interesting
interesting let's talk a little bit
about accuracy here as well because I
feel the I don't know is a really
important steps so that it reduces the
the kind of like levels of
hallucinations and things like that as
you mentioned equally a lot of the data
already exists in terms of the
documentation and I think in chatting
with you before I believe Kappa it it
can effectively site where it's grabbing
information from so it could potentially
give you an answer and then provide you
with a document that says here here's
where you can go to to get more data um
back from that in terms of the certainty
it being confident in its in its
responses what levels of feedback do you
get around that and secondly on URLs and
documents that don't exist is that a
problem or does it pretty much always
hit every time a document that people
can follow up with and read to make sure
if they wanted to that this is accurate
and the levels of depth they need yeah
I'll answer that that second part first
is I have not yet seen it make up a a
URL or or completely make up a a
document which again goes back to like
when I was doing early evaluation of
these tools and this AI agent technology
I did not want to risk having it do that
because based on our customers that we
have based on the interactions that I've
heard from like our support team that
was going to be wildly unacceptable and
to be honest it should be unacceptable
everywhere but this is still very early
technology right so there's a level of
risk associated with that and hopefully
most people go going into interacting
with these tools know that but one of
the most important things for me was a
tool that cited its sources and if we
needed to do any sort of validation or
checking we could go through and
basically like spot check so take a
random selection of conversations click
into those see what was going on for us
and for our user Behavior the
conversations are often quite short so
we're talking again more of the search
style so it's a couple of terms and then
an answer and then people leave I assume
they're getting what they need or maybe
they didn't get what they need but they
they made that decision quite quickly in
some cases we do see much longer
dialogue but again I'm comforted by the
fact that if I go in and read through
that discussion there's a back and forth
between Kappa and the user that are
helping the two of of them understand is
the user getting what they need is Kappa
serving what the user needs so you're
able to see the person say yes this is
what I'm looking for or could you give
me more information on something
specific and almost watch them walk
through a tree to get the the answer
that they're looking for that said I do
monthly reviews to make sure that things
are working as expected that on the
dashboard itself we're able to see where
Kappa Flags something
as a uncertain answer but we're also
able to see user generated feedback so
users can go through and give a thumbs
up thumbs down they can report issues
that they're seeing and that's something
that of course we monitor very closely I
was going to say is that feedback for
you or is that feedback for the to can
it learn from if it sees it's getting
some thumbs up it'll say Okay that was
good I'll use that for similar questions
I'll make sure I use that style of
answer again yeah so there is some
amount of that going on but for the most
part it's going to be feedback to me and
my team to say is this written in a way
that not only humans can read but that
Kappa or other AI tools can read as well
because we know we have customers coming
in and and leveraging those AI agents to
to read our docs so in that sense it
becomes yet another Persona that we need
to write for and I think that there's at
least the the general discourse that I'm
hearing right now is we don't want to
lean too heavily on things that start to
get us into like prompt engineering like
we're not writing the doc specifically
so that it can be consumed by an AI
agent but it's something that we keep in
mind to say is it clear enough for both
AI agents and humans to be able to parse
this in a way that they get what they
need which is why I say it's yet another
Persona that we have to think about but
again it's almost enforcing good hygiene
in that sense you should be citing
sources you should be linking in between
different areas of the technical
documentation to give people the amount
of information they're looking for and
that's all things that we do but we
validate that with how people are
interacting with the Kappa agent how
it's responding and it's a good gut
check for us to say are we doing our due
diligence to make this information
available I think with the citations I
think it's a really strong trust piece
as well whereby if someone can see that
if there isn't a dock there isn't some
static dock that says these are the
rules this is what you have to do this
is the workflow whatever you just rely
on an llm saying this is how you should
do it and sometimes yeah people have
different levels of Trust on that and I
guess the fact that there's a citation
there really helps in that trust I'd
love to talk a little bit about trust
generally I guess in terms of have you
seen varying levels of usage on the
agent in terms of people perhaps
starting off not trusting it as much or
or or trusting it more and more as they
get used to it do you have any data that
kind of shows the adoption based on
potentially trust it's all very
anecdotal in the sense that when we
first launched it I noticed people
having kind of those conversations where
they were playing with it and I think it
was do I trust this thing or more
generally do I trust this kind of
technology so I'm sure we've all been in
a situation where we're we're looking at
this thing going is this AI agent G to
like work with me to give me what I need
very early on I saw people doing that I
think some of it was even some of our
internal employees not doing things like
in an adversarial sense but again just
testing the limits of like how accurate
is this thing going to be so it's not
something that I monitor quite closely
but again it goes back to like spot
checking some of those conversations
seeing how things are are going and just
making sure that it's it's behaving in
that sense it's almost like yet another
report I'm managing like how how's the
performance going but no specific like
metrics around it that said there is a
portion of the tool where I get Source
analytic information so we have a number
of different sources that Kappa can use
not just the documentation and that's
something that I monitor too because I
want the documentation to continue to be
that source of Truth and kind of the
first place that it goes but it can also
grab some information from other areas
that includes things like our status
page that includes our Forum our
Marketplace B even our uh podcast
transcripts and when we start talking
about places where we have like
Community generated content and maybe
things like Forum discussions that are
quite lengthy we want to make sure that
it's citing the the most accurate thing
right so that's something that I watch
to see is it favoring things outside of
the docs what are those pieces of
information that it's favoring and I can
see at quite a granular level like
specific page PES or specific areas of
the Forum where it's maybe leaning a bit
more and again just spot checking to
make sure that's pulling up the best
information and it's not pulling up
someone's anecdotes about how they're
frustrated about their particular use
case or their particular question and we
don't want a tool that's reading that in
and saying you can't use kunda for this
particular use case because exactly one
individual ranted about it in some place
that's what I'm trying to avoid maybe
it's a little bit of paranoia but
something that I look for
absolutely it's interesting right
because the other thing you got to be
careful of course there is the data that
gets put into a forum like for example
podcast you control the content your
docs you control the content as soon as
you start thinking about forums my mind
goes straight away to okay what if I can
put a prompt injection into the forum
right or potentially misleading data or
data that's maybe even sensitive right
because I think it's one of those things
that it's user data at that stage right
are there within Kappa are there any
measures to take a look at what kind of
data it should and shouldn't look at is
there anything that you can set to avoid
using certain types of data so it's
going to come down to the source
analytics so I'm very careful about what
additional sources I I add in but then
of course within the source
configuration you can make sure that or
I guess you can double check do you want
to pull in everything do you want to
pull a subset of that information in so
our community has been around for a very
long time and we have
two different products at this point
kunda 7 kunda 8 are two different Source
codes and with that we have a very large
history on kunda 7 and the different use
cases that we enabled there and kunda 8
being the next product that we're
supporting and being a totally different
code base we wanted to make sure that it
understood the difference between those
two so there's things that we did like
we made a judgment call and saying let's
only reference the recent forum posts
what does that mean how many items does
that then pull in that's something that
we're also conscious of and then
refreshing and and checking does it make
sense for us to continue that strategy
so if I see something in the Forum where
I'm like o That's not like the most
accurate we can go through and remove it
from kappa's data set and again that's
something that's the regular maintenance
that goes on is you can't just deploy an
AI agent let it run I guess you could I
wouldn't do that
um I want to have a little bit of of due
diligence there to make sure is it
serving the best for our users and in
that sense does it have the freshest
content the most accurate content and if
we see it giving some strange answers
what do we need to do do we need to
remove that Forum topic do we need to do
a full refresh of recent Forum topics do
we need to limit what recent is and how
we Define it all of those things go into
the the discussions that are happening
behind the scenes really interesting and
I think there's a lot of challenges
there just in terms of making sure that
yeah not just is the data relevant but
is it at the same levels of versions and
things like that in terms of the
interactions between the agent and the
user let's say I didn't ask or I didn't
give it enough information and it maybe
has information on various versions how
good is it ask asking clarifying
questions and things like that will it
go ahead and try and get more data from
user or because I know a lot of llms
they're like they Trigger Happy in terms
of giving information sometimes without
enough data how does it deal with that
this implementation doesn't really do
any like additional questioning I
hesitate to say it's taking things at at
face value but I think the way that it
responds with giving the best answer
that it can based on the the information
that you provided but then it also very
quickly says for more details you can
refer to the communed documentation
you can maybe go to what it thinks is a
a relevant Forum post and then
occasionally you'll see people engage in
a dialogue with it and correct either
the question that they asked or if
they're really using it as a
superpowered search box you can see them
start to add more terms to it so the one
of the the topics that I was looking at
today was around parameters and
parameters for and the API context where
it was very clear that someone was
trying to get specific information not
only on what is this parameter mean or
how do you use it but in a specific
programming language context so Kappa
responds with a general here's what you
do then that person came back and said
can I have it in Spring and Kappa
responded with a code snippet from
here's if you have a spring boot
application with kunda here's how you
might use that parameter so in that
sense it's responding in a way that I
think elicits the user to maybe give a
little bit more information provide a
little bit more context it's not at a
point where it's like handholding them
through that experience yeah which I
guess it depends on the use case like
from a documentation point of view that
might actually be okay and that might
actually be a pref more preferable thing
because it's maybe 60% actually is going
to provide you with the right dock
straight away and if it's not the right
dock then it's not the relevant snippet
you could potentially say oh actually
here's a little bit more of a filter so
that you can work on this infrastructure
or or or ecosystem and and then it can
provide more detail there so I suppose
it's just in terms of the flow it might
actually might be the better way of uh
even doing it and again it depends what
you're looking for it depends maybe your
level of comfort with something like
this even in in this case that I'm I'm
thinking of right now Kappa goes on to
say the code provided is a hypothetical
example it might not work for your
context and to refer to the official
commoda documentation so it's really
Landing very heavily on here's what I
think you're looking for and please help
me validate that's correct and and
accurate and also do your homework don't
just copy and paste this out of the UI
and into your code because maybe it
doesn't work as intended amazing we're
going to jump into a little bit of a
screen share straight after this so for
those listening on the podcast hop over
to our YouTube channel and you'll be
able to see various dashboards and some
data from Kappa for those only watching
on the podcast thank you very much for
listening Mara it was real pleasure
chatting and it was a really great
insight to hear how you're using the AI
agent to be able to show or provide
answers to people with questions about
your documentation and usage so thank
you very much for sharing that it's been
a pleasure checking yeah thanks for
having me and I hope this encourages
people to take that risk I know for
people who like own documentation like I
do I was a little bit nervous at first
but I think that the tooling out there
is is really great I think there's a lot
of safeguards in place particularly now
whether you're using Kappa or something
else people use it we get a lot of
interaction and I think it's helpful so
definitely recommend but again thanks
for having me and letting me talk about
it oh no problem at all and thank you
everyone for listening and than you
tuning to the next session see you
[Music]
thanks thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by
Tessy than